Hey guys, welcome to another session, the Cybersecurity Frameworks.
I didn't prepare any presentations here.
I'd say, apparently, I don't need to waste my time in preparing the presentation.
So you can easily go to the Lock Herd Martin subsides, and you can search for a cyberkill
sign.
So you can easily get this.
So what's a cyberkill sign?
So it will be an important question in the interview, if you have refreshes, or if you are
going for any other jobs, if you are going to own domain to another domain.
So the cyberkill sign might attack framework, this two questions will be there.
So what's a cyberkill sign means?
Okay?
So let's take an example.
There are some threat tactics.
Or there's a attacker doing some attack.
So he need to follow some track, right?
So he need to go to step by step, okay?
The cyberkill chain and mitre, it will represent the path, how the attackers will achieve
their objective.
So if they're, motive is like attacking a company and doing a ransomware or uploading the
data from the companies are taking a command and control.
So how they will achieve their, uh, motive, how they will hack the company, uh, it will,
the cyberkill chain and mitre, this two framers will give a step by step explanations.
So how the attacker will achieve their objective, uh, if their objective is like anything.
So we need to hack the company and we need to delete some data or upload some data from
the company or we need to pull the ransomware, uh, instead of the company.
So this, uh, both framers will, will give the explanation about this.
So how the attacker, uh, complete their, uh, attack, uh, one by one, okay?
So this is the word adversary must complete in order to achieve their objective.
So how they are going to, uh, achieve their, uh, steps one by one.
So first we will see the, so APT can refer this term, advance persistent thread.
So you can give the, you can see the definition here, but I don't need to go, uh, for that.
Let's see the recognitions.
So in the recognitions part, uh, we are basically, we need to set our target right?
So the attacker will choose their target and they will gather some information about
their target.
Okay?
So let's take an example if I'm attacker, so I need to attack one of the company named, uh,
in Citrix or, uh, Cybertron, zero one or any other company.
So what I will do, uh, I, I can't able to, uh, go to the company and directly attack, uh,
into the machines, but you need to gather some data from the, from the company, okay?
So, you know, to gather some information about the company, what was the, uh, public
AP of the company, what was the email addresses they are using and, uh, how many employees
are working in their company and the employee's email address, some confidential information
if possible.
So you need to gather some information, okay?
This is like you are going to, uh, attack your enemy.
So but you were, you need to, uh, you need to understand what was the enemy, uh, Bikner's
or what was the, uh, what was the enemy you were thinking and, uh, as possible, you need
to get, uh, much information, okay?
So let's think of it.
That's called as the organization's part, we need, we are doing the same, uh, here.
So after doing the recognizes, trust me, we will see everything in the real time, in the
real attack, how I, how I will do the scanning and how I will, uh, do a organization,
everything we can see in the optimizations, don't worry about that, okay?
So, uh, I hope many of them, uh, feels like it's full of theory, um, don't, uh, don't
think like that, because theory is one of the important consequences of security, because, uh,
we need to understand the concepts, how it was working, so after understanding the concept
only, you can able to attack the companies, okay?
So the next part will be the weaponization, so the weaponization part, once you understand
the enemy, uh, your organization, for you need to develop your code, okay?
You need to develop your own program to attack the company, okay?
So you know how to attack the company now, because you are doing some recon part, and
the next part, you need to do some, uh, you have, if you have the program right, you need,
you need the tool, uh, to attack your enemy, or you need the, uh, program to attack the
organization, example of malware, okay?
So you need to do that, the weaponization part, the next part will be the delivery, so
after creating your own program, so you need to deliver the, that malware or program
into the target company, what you are targeting, uh, through, you can use the email, so
we, we gathered, uh, email information, sent recommendations, you can, uh, deliver, uh, your
payload in the email, the malicious code in the email, uh, USPR web, uh, any, uh, any option
is okay, uh, so whatever is, uh, feasible to you, anything is okay.
So once delivery, and let's start the exploitation, so once, uh, uh, delivering that, uh,
the forced of will be, if there, if it's a vulnerability, you can exploit that, you can,
you can, uh, exploit that vulnerability and get to the machine, and finally you can install
the malware, so after installing the malware, so malware is a malicious code, which you
have created, okay?
So after installing the malware, you will get a command and control, so command and control
means a reverse shell, uh, from, uh, from the, so of which you are targeted, so you can
control your, control the organization using the command and control, so it will open
a separate channel for you and the machine you have hacked, so you can perform all the
commands, uh, you can, uh, do whatever you want there, and the options and objectives will
be the, so after getting a command and control, so what are the things you are doing, okay?
What's your version of gold, something, uh, someone will be think, I need to hack the
organization and I need to, um, upload something into the organization, or I need to, uh,
install more malware into the organization, or, uh, or, uh, or I need to hack other machines
in the organization, so that's all will be, uh, they're in action and objective, okay?
So whatever you want to do, uh, example, deleting the data, modifying the data, and, uh,
stealing the credentials, username, password from the browsers, et cetera, a lot of things
you can do, okay?
So action and object will be you, so what are the things, the objectives like that, okay?
So my object will be, once I get into the machine, I need to ex-filtrate.
I need to, uh, upload the company, the credentials, company data into the cloud or into the
public, uh, public platform, uh, like that, so everyone will be like deleting the data,
uploading the data and, uh, targeting other machines, so that's depend upon the hackers.
Um, so action and object will be your objective, so what you want to do, you can
go ahead and you can, uh, do that, uh, objective, okay?
So that's all about the, uh, cyber kill-chain, so we will see the miter, uh, frame up in
the next section, and what are the possible, uh, interview questions you can face, uh,
here in the cyber kill-chain ad attack, attack framework, okay?
Uh, so let's hop of this video, and we will continue our, uh, discussion in the next
video.
See you guys.
Bye-bye.